I'm sure that that will happen because
some of the changes that are happening
under the Trump administration are all
else equal going to slow the the US
economy down in the near term. We like
to talk about generational wealth for
younger people. It's important to uh
explain why you think it's going to
appreciate. I'd like to hear the the
case. And often times if someone makes a
case for an investment and they listen
to themselves make it, they'll either
become more confident or they'll lose
their conviction. I we got to a point
where there just were, you know, people
were were too bullish. I think right now
sentiment is swinging so negatively that
we're probably close to levels where you
want to be, you know, you want to be
pretty aggressive. I think that the
global financial system in large part
will be will be built on top of
Ethereum. The US could have a recession
right now. You're starting to see Scott
Bessent suggest that yeah, maybe maybe
there is one. He doesn't want to predict
it. Trump's unwilling to suggest that
there won't be one. No one could no one
can ever tell you that there will never
be a recession. But I think the the way
that they're talking about it suggests
to me in order to actually really make
some significant money, there needs to
be. We're joined by Eric Peters right
now at the Digital Asset Summit in New
York. He's the CEO of One River Asset
Management and the CEO of Coinbase Asset
Management. We'll be talking about his
views on uh the crypto landscape.
Welcome to the show. Thank you, David.
Nice to see you, David. and Bonnie.
Eric, good to see you. Let's talk about
uh your weekly newsletter that you have
on White River Assass Management. You
can check that out. Uh last week or I
believe the last issue that you had, you
talked about the potential geopolitical
risks of Trump's kind of taking a step
back from Ukraine and what that implies
for Europe. So, if Europe were to
remilitarize, specifically Germany, what
does that do to the fiscal position?
What does that do for the markets? It's
a really interesting uh situation. I
mean, in my career, I so I've been doing
this for over 35 years, and the Germans
have been the most fiscally austere
country in Europe, the largest economy.
And so, kind of what Germany does, the
rest of Europe is more or less forced to
do. So, for the first time in my career,
I've seen them really lift what they
call the debt break. So, it's just it
will allow for very substantial deficit
spending, and I think they need to do
it. Um, it'll be interesting to hit the
world at a point where, you know, I
think global growth is pretty decent
right now and, uh, Europe starting to
spend money and and build big deficits
will just mean, you know, I think higher
inflation, all else equal. Does that
imply that the debt break is going to be
broken? Yeah, they'll lift it. I mean,
that's it. It it should happen this week
in terms of being approved uh by
legislators, but that that's going to
happen. But you're not worried about a
hyperinflation scenario like the with
the Wimar Republic, right? No, no, no.
That's what they've been worried about
for so long. I mean, they've been
they've been scared by their ghost of
however many, you know, 80 plus years
past, uh, which is the source of their
fiscal austerity, but that I think I
think the combination of the US pulling
back from NATO and from Europe and
what's happening in Ukraine has been the
catalyst that's pushed them into this
position. So once they have this larger
levels of debt and once we have
potentially higher levels of inflation,
I mean that's more of a longer term
medium-term trend. Does this have any
market impact whatsoever? I think so. I
mean, you're seeing European equities
substantially outperform the US over the
past, you know, 3 4 months. Yeah. Um I
think all else equal, we'll see higher
rates out of Europe. We should see a
stronger euro. Uh and I think those are
those are trends that fly in the face of
how the market has been positioned for a
long period of time. So pretty dramatic
market moves expect the US economy to
continue growing at a faster rate than
Europe.
I think not immediately uh just because
I think the some of the changes that are
happening under the Trump administration
are all else equal going to slow the the
US economy down in the in the near term.
I think the goal is to put it on a more
sustainable position to to continue to
outperform over the longer term, but
we'll have to see. We got to get through
the first the first stage of this
readjustment first. Okay, cool. Well,
um, crypto community, we like to talk
about generational wealth, right? But,
you know, young people, they don't have
a lot saved up. Let's say somebody has
50K, 100K on the sideline. What would
you suggest they invest in?
And is the question uh to be focused
exclusively on crypto? It doesn't have
to. Yeah, I think look I think for
younger people it's important to uh
uh to make investments across assets
really um not not to be entirely focused
on crypto. I think crypto's super
exciting. There are a lot of young
people who made an awful lot of money in
crypto. There are also a lot of young
people who who've lost money. So um you
know I think with with any like with my
kids for instance so you know my my kids
are probably the the generation of the
the folks that uh that are your audience
um they're invested in crypto they're
invested in traditional financial assets
equity indices and things like that. I
think the most important thing is to
just start investing, start saving some
money, putting it into a combination of
assets, some of which you think have a
lot of upside and others which you think
you can reliably depend on as being
around in the next, you know, 10 years.
There's certain crypto assets where you
you can't say that. There are others
where like I think for instance, Bitcoin
will certainly be around in in 10 years.
I think it'll be worth an awful lot more
money than it is right now. But they're,
you know, they're they're far more
speculative assets in uh in crypto as
well that I couldn't say the same thing
about. They might be worth a lot more
next month or next year, next quarter.
Um but they might be worth a lot less
in, you know, in five years or 10 years
as well. So if your kid comes to you and
be like, "Dad, I want to invest in
memecoin." What would you say?
Generally, I'm generally not. But I but
you know I I hate I hate to micromanage
anyone. So I'd say I I wouldn't just say
don't do that. I would say explain why
you think it's going to appreciate
you're like you're you're you're buying
it not because you think it's going to
go down. You think it's going to go up
hopefully. I think my kids are smart
enough to figure that out. Uh and so I'd
like I'd like to hear the the case. And
often times if someone makes a case for
an investment and they listen to
themselves make it, they'll either
um become more confident or they'll lose
their conviction. So I try to not tell
people what to do. Well, we do want to
ask you about your Bitcoin price
prediction if you're comfortable talking
about that. Um maybe the price
prediction of 2025 and 2026. what has to
happen for this price target to hit?
Yeah, you know, digital assets uh have
been awfully weak recently actually,
which I I think is I think what happened
um more of an explanation than just a
specific target. But I I think there was
such an abundance of extremely positive
news uh that came out post election that
for the time being these assets ran they
ran out of new
buyers. Um you know there was so much
good news priced into the market and I
think what we've experienced over the
last few months is that we've had a
continuation of reasonably good news and
the prices have fallen.
So my experience over, you know, yeah,
over a few decades has been the markets
that you really want to want to be long
um aggressively or markets that are
starting to behave well when the news is
poor. And we're not quite there yet in
digital assets. I think like I have
long-term positions and I'm
I'm, you know, substantially bullish
over the next, you know, 5, 10 years,
two years for that matter. Um, but I
think there's probably still some
selling that has to happen right now. I
think um, but I think
what we got to a point where there just
were, you know, people were were too
bullish. I think right now sentiment is
swinging so negatively that we're
probably close to levels where you want
to be, you know, you want to be pretty
aggressive. And uh, and then I, you
know, then I think, look, I think
there's great legislation that's coming
out. Uh, the regulatory developments in
the US are really positive. Um, I think
that we're going to see a crypto reserve
out of the US. I think we're starting to
see more signs of how that gets funded,
which is very creative and actually
quite powerful. Uh, so I think some of
the building blocks are happening for
this next wave. Um, we're not quite
there yet. Is a negative sentiment
you're talking about exclusive to
cryptos or is it risk assets overall? In
other words, are we talking about a
divergence of Bitcoin versus stocks or a
continuation of correlation here?
I think that the the negative uh
negative sentiment is across all risk
assets and I think what's happened over
the past year or so is as crypto's been
integrated into the traditional
financial markets through ETFs and
whatnot starting to it's starting to
behave at least for the time being more
like a traditional risk asset. Uh and so
as you've seen I mean crypto actually
led this equity move down. Crypto is the
first one. crypto tends to bottom before
other markets, tends to top before other
markets. So, I think it it has for this
correction as well. Uh but but sentiment
is sentiment is significantly negative.
I think it could I think like the US
could have a recession right now. You're
starting to see Scott Bessant suggest
that yeah, maybe maybe there is one. He
doesn't want to predict it. Trump's
unwilling to suggest that there won't be
one. No one could no one can ever tell
you that there will never be a recession
or there won't be a recession. Um, but I
think the the way that they're talking
about it suggests to me that they're
prepared to have what they would hope to
be a relatively shallow recession for
one or two quarters to set themselves up
for a pretty robust economy heading into
midterms. Sure. I also want to ask you
about Ethereum because as I was doing
the research, there was this one
interview that you said you think the
global financial system will be built on
Ethereum, but you know the sentiment and
the community is people are pretty
disappointed with the performance. Now I
want to ask you how you think now
because that interview was like a couple
months ago. Yeah, I think that that's
absolutely the case. So I think I think
that the global financial system in
large part will be will be built on top
of
Ethereum. Uh I think what Ethereum is
suffering from in addition to just
general risk sentiment
is that we haven't we haven't seen that
building at scale yet. And so while over
the past couple years Ethereum has
become a lot cheaper to use, it has
become far faster. all things that will
accommodate its use as that base layer
for global finance. Um, you know, a lot
of the layer 2s are taking a lot of the
economics that would have otherwise
acred to Ethereum. I think that in the
near- term that's negative for for the
price of Ethereum and people are pretty
pessimistic as a result of that, but
having having speeds increase to this
degree and having prices come down for
its usage is fantastic for adoption. So
now I think what happens this year is we
get the the regulations that allow that
development to actually start happening
and then my guess is my guess is in 26
we'll start seeing a lot more real kind
of tradi developments on
Ethereum. I don't know how I don't know
how far the market has to look out uh in
order to to price that in. But I think
once the market starts seeing that real
trady stuff is being built on Ethereum,
I think it'll be extremely positive and
it'll come from a place where prices are
really quite low and Simeon is horrific
in Ethereum. How does that translate to
the Ethereum price like the usage? Yes,
the Treadfi are built on top of
Ethereum, but as you said, layer 2 is
taking all the benefits. It it is right
now, but Ethereum can evolve. I think I
think they're pretty focused on making
sure that the price just is that that
all of the economics don't acrue to the
layer twos. Um there are a number of
things that they'll be able to do I
think and will probably happen over the
next year to make sure that that um the
balance between where the fees are paid
is more equitable. Um I I I'm I'm sure
that that will happen.
Um going back to markets for just a
minute now. One river asset management
has a um well they have number of
reports but from last October you wrote
in uh in this particular report that
investors should brace for uncertainty.
Specifically the hesitance of investors
to fully embrace uncertainty creates
opportunities for those who do.
Volatility being a measurement of
uncertainty is arguably the most direct
way to improve the uncertainty premium
into a portfolio. So I'm curious to how
you build this premium into this
portfolio and have a follow-up to that.
Yeah, we trade a lot in volatility
markets. Um volatility is really a
measure of uncertainty. Um and so I
think you know when number one, one of
the principles I'm speaking about there
is if you're ever really going to
produce substantial returns, you need to
be willing to invest in uncertain
environments. All right? So like we're
talking right now about Ethereum. You
asked a very good
question. Uh even if global finance is
is built on Ethereum, what hap you know
why will the price necessarily go up if
all the value acrrues to the layer twos
and so it's a good question. The answer
is if if it never does then Ethereum
price probably won't go up. I think
there's a lot of uncertainty around well
how will that get worked out? And the
statement I made is I think there are a
number of mechanisms that could happen
over the next year or two where they
figure out how to split those fees in a
more equitable way. But that's
uncertain. But that's the type of
uncertainty that I think as an investor
you need to look at and you need to go,
okay, well, how do I think the world is
going to play out here? I think
everything's going to be built on
Ethereum. Um, it's been around the
longest. It's the most stable. It's gone
through all these different upgrade
cycles.
um it's very secure you know so
therefore I think this will be the
foundation right but you don't make any
money from it right now and the price
keeps falling so I think you need to you
need to look for situations like that
and say well how that resolves is
uncertain at this stage um but when I
when I look at the players involved and
I think about what that future looks
like I think that there's a much higher
probability than the market currently
does that Ethereum is not only that base
layer but also acruise a lot more fees.
And so that's the the the formation of
any investment thesis more or less looks
like that. But I think in order to
actually really make some significant
money, there needs to be or at least the
market's view needs to be that there's a
lot of uncertainty. You might not have
that much uncertainty. Like I have I
have quite high conviction that what I
just said is going to be true. But I
think the market views that as being
very uncertain still, which is why the
prices are so depressed.
Um, do you believe in four-year cycle
where Bitcoin rallies first and then big
cap, small cap, and then all the meme
coins, but this cycle looks a little
different. So, I want to know your
thoughts. Yeah, I think this cycles I I
I don't believe in the four-year cycle.
Um, so, uh, which is not to say that it
hasn't happened. It's just I think there
there may have been a a cycle and a good
reason for that cycle. I think with the
um the amount of new supply that comes
out of miners right now, probably a
pretty reasonable
um explanation or why that cycle would
be a bit different. But I also think
that the types of players that are
investing in this space at this stage
are so different from you know looking
back four years ago, eight years
ago, 12 years ago that um I I just think
it's unlikely that it's going to play
out with that same type of four-year
cycle. I think the more institutions
that come and invest in this space uh
the less we'll see those same types of
cycles and even correlations like we're
talking you were asking the question
David about um you know is uh is is
sentiment depressed just for this asset
class or also is it is it connected to
equities and other risk assets and I
think you know those types of
correlations I think are likely to
change over the coming 4 8 12 years
relative to the last you know 4 8 12
just because the types of players are
different the size of the market the
market cap is very different
a lot of traders though they chase this
rotation right um it goes from Bitcoin
and then they go Ethereum so now that
you said there is no four-year cycle
what do you believe in
I I look at um I mean to me when I first
got involved in a serious way into
digital assets. I'd always I'd punted
Bitcoin around personally for quite a
while, but we made our first big
investments in 2020 just after the
election. And I at the time I looked at
it and I said, I have a
feeling like based on everything that I
see in terms of this market structure
that there's going to be a very powerful
probably 10-year run for these assets.
And so why did I pick I mean that's an
arbitrary number. Okay. So I mean
certainly don't hold it hold me to it
but the thought was that at the time in
2020 we had had you know Bitcoin and
other assets had had multiple cycles.
They had survived that and actually
still even thrived through it. So it
didn't look like a traditional um bubble
of of some of of sorts. But there were
so many things that continue to be
misunderstood about these assets and
very few people could actually buy them.
I mean, it was diff it's not they
couldn't, it was just difficult. The
frictions to buy were very high. And so
my view was it's probably going to take
10 years until everyone has a digital
wallet on their phone and understands
what these assets are. um institutions
will have adopted them in a significant
way and at that stage they probably have
achieved the type of price that's just
it's less convex to the upside meaning
there's in 10 years you're you're
probably not going to say Bitcoin could
go up another 20x or 50x you might say
it could go up you know like maybe like
the stock market it could go up five or
15 or 20% a year but I I I still feel
like we're on that track there's still
So there's so few institutions that have
really allocated this space and there's
still so much that's misunderstood about
it that I think there's still there's
sufficient uncertainty about it its
future path that I think there's still
quite a bit of upside. It's great news.
That's a good segue to uh project
diamond something that Coinbase asset
management is working on. So I believe
currently 0.25% of global finance is on
chain. What is a reasonable
percentage that makes sense for you in
the future and what is a road to that
growth? So when when we when we entered
this space and we built out a crypto
asset manager what we realized is that
there are many different crypto assets
to invest in but most of them are very
tiny. So from an institutional
perspective, we felt, you know what, for
this industry to ever become something
really big, we need to bring traditional
financial assets onchain. And so Project
Diamond is something we worked on for 3
years. It's Coinbase now owns it. Uh,
and it is a it is a tool to help
institutions bring bonds and equities
uh, and issue them in a digitally native
uh, form and then exchange them with one
another. So buy and sell them. And so
that is really the that's the unlock. So
everything that's happened in crypto so
far has happened in this crypto economy,
this crypto universe, Bitcoin, ETH and
the the trail of
assets. That's as as you said is 25
basis points of total global assets. The
big unlock for crypto is taking the
crypto technology and and bringing that
the rest of that massive pile of assets
into this crypto economy so that stocks
and bonds and real estate and art can be
traded in the same way that Bitcoin or
ETH can be traded. So that that's what
we built. And in terms of how fast that
will happen, I think what this industry
has been waiting for has been waiting
for the regulatory changes that are
going to happen this year. So, you know,
Genius Act looks like that's going to
get through fit 21. We I would expect
that to be done before the August recess
of Congress and then all the traditional
financial players will have clarity
around the whole structure of crypto
crypto assets, what does the SEC do,
what's the role of the CFTC, what's a
security, what's a commodity, what's a
collectible, for instance. There will be
all sorts of clarity around that along
with stable coin. And that is what's
going to allow all the big financial
players to say, "Okay, you know what?
These technologies are faster, better,
cheaper, more secure. Let's let's start
trading our equities on crypto rails.
Let's start trading our the bond market
on crypto rails. Let's start trading
credit on crypto rails. Let's start
doing real estate." How fast will that
happen? I think it will be slow and then
really fast. In other words, I think
there will be some adoption probably
starting with equities. Um and there
have already been some announcements
about firms that are looking to to do
something in that space. Um meaning
issue equities as crypto, you know, as
crypto securities. Um so I think that
that will be the beginning of it. And
then depending on how fast some of the
big financial institutions jump on
board, what what you'll see is you'll
see the ones that are the early adopters
achieve some economies of scale. They'll
start saving money. They'll be able to
execute faster for their clients. All
all good things. and then the
competitive pressures will will bring
other people in that market. But I would
say that it won't be a massive amount
over the next year. I think in 5 years
that 25 basis point number will be many
multiples of what it is right now.
Um and then after that then the then the
acceleration will really take place. I'm
very curious how do you prove ownership
of real estate on chain? Meaning if I'm
trading this tokenized real estate token
Yeah. How do I know it's actually that
building? Well, it has to be connected
to law. So, you know, I think the
um these are the you know, that's a very
good question and one of many that have
to get answered over the next few years.
But essentially, you know, when you with
Bitcoin or ETH, it's very easy right
now. Um but when you have to take this
token and you have to attach it to a
some asset that is in the real world
whether it could be could be gold it
could be real estate it could be a piece
of art you need to attach that to law
and it needs to be you know governed in
a particular jurisdiction and so those
are the things that will get worked out
over the next few years and they're
tricky to work out but they'll get
worked out. Is the White House talking
about it? Oh I'm sure.
Uh I have one more question for you.
Yeah, shoot. So you're an asset manager.
You've been in the space for many many
years. What is your viewpoint on the
efficient market hypothesis? I've
interviewed Eugene Thma actually and um
you know his view and many others in his
space. Academics believe that you can't
really beat the markets long term unless
you have asymmetric
information. What's your response to
that?
I think
um I think for most people that's
probably the safe way to think about it.
Um but for practitioners I think you're
I think your job is to is to try to
glean information
um that is asymmetric and that's not
saying inside information. Obviously
there are people who would love to have
inside information and would trade on it
um but that's not what I'm talking
about. and and there are people in in
the past who have, right? And so that's
obviously what does it mean for you as a
NASA manager? I think you're you're
looking for um you're trying to bring
your experience to bear to look for
different configurations of
um asymmetries and people's
understanding of markets relative to to
kind of your understanding of the
market. So for instance, when I when I
described our entry into into Bitcoin, I
did enough in 2020, I did enough work to
look at that and
say most institutional investors right
now think that you can't you can't store
it securely, that it's mostly used by,
you know, drug dealers or whatever it
may be, that there is a tremendous
amount of financial crime that happens
on these networks. And I looked at I
looked at it and and they also thought
well it's just digital. You could make
an infinite number of Bitcoin. You know
there there were a lot of misconceptions
about that and I looked at that and said
actually most of the concerns that these
people have are unfounded at this stage.
Actually you can secure Bitcoin securely
through Coinbase for instance which is
the you know who we used initially. um
it is used for some financial crime but
so are dollars and it's actually far
less and there's there's a a very strong
crypto paper trail um to see what bad
actors are doing. So like every argument
that institutions had for not being
involved were actually less valid or
invalid. And
so the asymmetry of understanding that
is that it's like, okay, in a world
where I think there's going to be more
inflation, which is what we thought in
2020 because of the the vast fiscal
stimulus, investors are going to look
around for things that are relatively
scarce. And what are they going to buy?
Probably going to buy some gold. Maybe
they'll buy some housing.
They might buy Bitcoin. And by the way,
every single institutional investor that
I've talked to misunderstands it. So all
they have to do is understand it just a
little bit better. and there's going to
be incremental buying. What's the major
misunderstanding I'll end it here for me
of Bitcoin? The major misunderstanding
at that stage from an institution's
perspective is is that it can't be
stored safely. Like they just believe
that oh my god because you know there
were so many stories about people who
had their Bitcoin on their laptop and
they lost their laptop or they lost
their key and institutions can't afford
that to happen. So they that was
probably the biggest one. The second
biggest one, maybe they were tied first
place, is that you could just create a
new Bitcoin network, right? And so why
would there be any value that would
acrue to this network? Those are
two obvious
misconceptions and that nevertheless
investors had. So you know that when you
can identify periods like that, you have
you have a real advantage. So efficient
market hypothesis I think it's often
right particularly in very efficient
markets but uh as an investment manager
what you look for is you look for those
unique configurations of opportunities
where you go I think I have a real edge
here. I think what I've learned from all
this and talking to a lot of people in
this space is that the better you are as
an asset manager the better you are at
finding information to your advantage.
I'm not talking about insider
information. I'm talking about
identifying things that you could use as
information. No doubt. And uh just come
from experience. Yeah. You know, I I
have a vast network. And the reason that
networks of other smart investors are
really helpful is that they're all, you
know, they're all cultivating their own
source of information and they're
curating them. And by the time you have
a conversation with another investor
who's really done a lot of homework, um
you're gleaning something from them. And
if you can kind of triangulate that with
a number of other folks, you can develop
the type of view that I just described.
And uh those can be very powerful. You
don't have to you don't have to find
them all the time either. That's the
reason why the audience wants you,
right? They're trying to Good point.
There you go. You're helping to give the
uh common investor an edge by listening
to you talk. Well, thank you. It's been
a real pleasure, David. Thank you.
Bonnie, thank you so much. Shia.